Anshum Gupta

Software Engineer - Search @ Apple, Apache Lucene/Solr committer

Summary

Apache Lucene/Solr committer and PMC member with experience in Search engine design and development. Spend all of my time working on distributed search a.k.a. SolrCloud.

A part of the search team at Apple, building and scaling SolrCloud to new levels.

Experience

Software Engineer - Search at Apple

May 2017 - Present

Apache Lucene PMC Member at The Apache Software Foundation

February 2015 - Present

A project management committee (PMC) is a committee of the Apache Software Foundation charged with responsibility for a top level project. The PMC is the vehicle through which decision making power and responsibility for oversight is devolved to developers.

http://lucene.apache.org/whoweare.html

Apache Lucene/Solr Committer at The Apache Software Foundation

February 2014 - Present

My recent works primarily include adding features to SolrCloud (Distributed features of Apache Solr).

Senior Software Engineer - Watson Search at IBM

September 2015 - May 2017 (1 year 9 months)

Search Guy at Watson @ IBM Almaden Research Center

Software Engineer at Lucidworks

January 2013 - September 2015 (2 years 9 months)

Part of the Lucidworks Open Source team. I work almost full time on open source issues not restricted to, but primarily centered around SolrCloud.

Software Development Engineer, Amazon CloudSearch at A9.com

September 2011 - December 2012 (1 year 4 months)

Was part of the team at A9 that launched AWS CloudSearch, the first AWS search service.

For more info check http://aws.amazon.com/cloudsearch/

Software Development Engineer at Amazon.com

September 2011 - December 2012 (1 year 4 months)

Search Architect at Cleartrip.com

June 2010 - September 2011 (1 year 4 months)

Primary contributor and lead for SmallWorld product backend at Cleartrip. Built a travel search service using Apache Lucene for the same.

Search Architect at Naukri.com

2009 - June 2010 (1 year 6 months)

Was a primary contributor in the design and development of the Job Search and Recruitment Search (Resdex) engines built at Naukri.com.

Among other things, also built the following:

- * Recommendation engine
- * Click predictor
- * Resume parser and injection pipeline

Sr. Software Developer at Naukri.com

2006 - 2009 (4 years)

Software Engineer at Infosys Technologies Ltd

2005 - 2006 (2 years)

Education

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

B.Tech, Computer Science, 2001 - 2005

Bhatnagar International School

1997 - 2000

Manav Sthali School

1993 - 1999

Anshum Gupta

Software Engineer - Search @ Apple, Apache Lucene/Solr committer



Contact Anshum on LinkedIn